iie.org 2019-12-17

# Privacy Policy

_Disclaimer_

The information provided on this website is not official U.S. Government information and does not represent the views or positions of the U.S. Agency for International Development or the U.S. Government.

**Last Updated: May 2018**

### Introduction

At the Institute of International Education (“IIE”), we understand that privacy is an important issue for visitors to our Website, and your privacy is equally important to us. This Privacy Policy ("Policy"), which is part of our **Terms and Conditions** , covers the treatment of the personal information we collect when you visit this website or any other website we operate (the "Website").

If you visit or interact with the Website, you are signifying to us that you consent to this Policy and the ways we collect, use, process and transfer your personal data as described here. **We may change this Policy, and will post any changes here. If you continue to access or use the Website after we post the changed Policy, we consider you to have accepted the changed Policy. If you do not agree to this Policy, please do not access or use the Website**. We will post a **“LAST UPDATED”** legend at the top of the Policy.

Under the European Data Protection Legislation (if it applies to you) and other applicable law, IIE is the **data controller** responsible for the processing of your Personal Information collected from and through the Website. IIE is the sole owner of any information collected on the Website. For certain Programs we administer for sponsors, IIE is a **data processor** of Personal Information that is collected from applicants, participants, partners and others in connection with these Programs. This Policy applies to the Personal Information collected from and through the Website. IIE Programs and sponsored Programs we administer may have additional or different data privacy policies and practices. These are disclosed at the points where data is collected for those Programs.

### Country-Specific Provisions

The Schedules appearing at the end of this Policy describe modifications of certain parts of this Policy that might apply to you if you reside in a country identified in a Schedule or if you submit information to an IIE office located in a country identified in a Schedule. Please review the Schedules to determine if any of the modifications apply to you.

### European Data Protection Legislation

In this Policy, **"European Data Protection Legislation"** means all applicable legislation relating to data protection in the European Economic Area ( **"EEA")** , including the EU General Data Protection Regulation 2016/679 ( **"GDPR"** ) and all laws adapted under or replacing the GDPR. Where this Policy uses terms specially defined in the GDPR, the GDPR definitions apply.

If the GDPR applies to you, your specific rights are listed at the end of this Policy.

### Information You Provide to Us

**Personal Information Examples** means data relating to you from which you can be reasonably identified. Examples include your full name, date of birth, gender, email address, postal address, telephone number, job title, educational institution, financial information and your employer.

When you communicate your Personal Information to us through the Website, we will tell you at each collection point what information is required and what we use it for. You can choose not to enter some or all your Personal Information, but if you do so, we might not be able to respond to your query, communicate further with you and/or provide the requested services.

### How We Use Your Data

As allowed by law and unless this Policy states otherwise elsewhere, we will use your Personal Information as described below.

**Information We Collect Directly**

You may visit the Website without being required to provide your name, email address or other personal information. Some features of the Website might include features or services that permit you to enter contact information and other information about you, such as your name, address and e-mail address. Depending on why and how you communicate with us via the Website, we will use your Personal Information as follows:

  * **If you are inquiring about programs or services we provide or administer:** to respond to your query and/or give you information you request.
  * **If you are inquiring about how your organization could support or work with IIE: **to consider whether it would be beneficial to work with your organization. We will let you know when we need your Personal Information in order to perform an agreement with you or your organization or to comply with a legal obligation.
  * **If you are member of the public and you inquire about employment with us:** to consider and decide how to respond to your query.
  * **If you have any other inquiry:** to consider and respond to your inquiry.
  * **If we do not know you or your organization: **to confirm your identity, your organization and your role.
  * **If you are submitting a comment on a Bulletin Board or Chat Area:** to publish your comment on the grounds that by clicking “submit,” you consented to our posting your Personal Information on the Bulletin Board or Chat Area selected by you. You may withdraw your consent to our using your Personal Information this way by amending or deleting your comment or by contacting us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org). If you withdraw your consent, it will not change how we used your Personal Information before you withdrew that consent, but the comment will not be displayed in the future.
  * **If you opt-in to receive marketing communications:** to share information about our programs, services, news and events. When you enter your contact details for this reason and click “sign up,” you will be consenting to us contacting you for these purposes. We will only send you marketing communications if you have consented.

When you opt-in to receive marketing communications from us, you are giving your consent for your Personal Information to be used by us to contact you by email, direct mail and/or telephone as shown on the consent form, and to deliver personalized website experiences, to share information about relevant products, services, best practice information, industry news and events. You may to withdraw your consent or amend your communication preferences by contacting us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) or clicking the “unsubscribe” button at the bottom of any email you receive from us.

If you later decide you do not want to receive correspondence from us, such as communications regarding available Programs, press releases, newsletters, marketing, promotions, or other topics, simply click the “unsubscribe” link provided in that email message. Withdrawing your consent will not affect our use of the Personal Information prior to you withdrawing your consent, but it will mean that we will not contact you about available Programs, press releases, newsletters, marketing, promotions or other topics in the future.

**Information We Collect Automatically**

When you interact with the Website, we automatically collect information about your use of the Website from your browser in the Website server logs. Whenever you request a page through your browser, the navigation and clickstream data, such as your IP address, browser (and version), operating system, date, time, and the site from which you came are stored in a log file. We use software to create summaries from these statistics so we can evaluate content worth, Website and system administration, and anonymous user analysis. We use “cookie” technology on our Website. Cookies let us identify a user’s computer (so, for example, you won’t have to log in every time you visit the Website), and can help make it easier to navigate through the Website (cookies can record a user’s preferences and other data about the user’s Website visit).

When you use the Website for the first time, cookies that are essential to make the Website operate (“essential cookies”) will have been set, but other cookies will not have been set unless you agreed to those cookies being set at that time. If you have agreed to accept cookies, then the Website will remember this and continue to set cookies each time you visit.

Some cookies are deleted when you close your browser. These are known as “session cookies.” Others remain on your device until they expire or you delete them. These are known as “persistent cookies.” They enable us to remember things about you as a returning visitor. If you do not want cookies to be stored, you may turn off cookies individually, or you can select the appropriate options on your web browser to delete some or all cookies. However, if you block some or all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to use or access all or parts of the Website, such as being able to log on to member specific areas.

**Essential Cookies**  
Essential cookies enable you to navigate the Website and to use its services and features. Without these necessary cookies, the Website will not perform as smoothly for you as we would like it to and we may not be able to provide the Website or certain services or features.

Cookie | Provider | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
website#lang | Sitecore | This cookie tracks a user's language selection. The name of the cookie varies based on the configured site name. | Expires when the session ends  
ASP.NET_SessionId | Microsoft.Net | Randomly generated value used to track an active session. | Expires when the session ends  
  
**Social Media Cookies**  
Social media cookies are used to enable you to share pages and content you find interesting on our Website through third-party social networking and other websites. These cookies may also be used for advertising purposes.

Cookie | Provider | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
ref_page_url | Twitter | Part of Twitter's embedded services on the Websites (likes, sharing etc.). More information about Twitter’s use of cookies can be found in their [cookie policy](https://help.twitter.com/en/rules-and-policies/twitter-cookies). | Expires when the session ends  
lang | Twitter | Remembers the user's selected language version of a website. | Expires when the session ends  
_twitter_sess | Twitter | Used in conjunction with the Twitter social plugins in order to allow following our Twitter accounts easily, sharing content via Twitter, and displaying the latest tweet. | < 1 year  
auth_token | Twitter | Used in conjunction with the Twitter social plugins in order to allow following our Twitter accounts easily, sharing content via Twitter, and displaying the latest tweet. | < 1 year  
csrf_same_site_set | Twitter | Enable us to track visitor activity from our Twitter ads on our website, and also to allow users to share content from our websites. | 2 years  
guest_id | Twitter | Twitter cookie appears on pages that use the button "Tweet" and serves to identify the user with a unique number associated with Twitter specific cookies. | 2 years  
kdt | Twitter | Twitter cookie appears on pages that use the button "Tweet" and serves to identify the user with a unique number associated with Twitter specific cookies. | 2 years  
personalization_id | Twitter | This cookie is set due to Twitter integration and sharing capabilities for the social media. | 2 years  
remember_checked_on | Twitter | Determine if user logged in during browser session; allow tweets; record number of times a page is tweeted. | 10 years  
twid | Twitter |  Determine if user logged in during browser session; allow tweets; record number of times a page is tweeted. | 10 years  
metrics_token | Twitter | Provide Twitter syndication. | 2 years  
FORMASSEMBLY | FormAssembly | Donate form. | 25 years  
JSESSIONID | FormAssembly | JSESSIONID is a ID generated by Servlet container like Tomcat or Jetty and used for session management in J2EE web application for http protocol. The ID is sent to the client either within a cookie (default) or as part of the URL (called URLrewriting, used only if cookies are disabled on the browser). | Expires when the session ends  
  
**Analytics Cookies**  
Analytics cookies collect information about your use of the Website, and enable us to improve the way it works. For example, analytics cookies show us which are the most frequently visited pages on the Website, help us record any difficulties you have with the Website, and show us whether our advertising is effective or not. Analytics cookies allow us to see the overall patterns of usage on the Website, rather than the usage of a single person. We use information from analytics cookies to analyze the Website traffic, but we do not examine this information for individually identifying information.

Cookie | Provider | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
_ga | Google Analytics | Stores the Client ID | 2 years  
_gat_UA | Google Analytics | This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites. | < 1 day  
_gid | Google Analytics | Used to distinguish users. | 24 hours  
JSESSIONID | New Relic | JSESSIONID is a ID generated by Servlet container like Tomcat or Jetty and used for session management in J2EE web application for http protocol. The ID is sent to the client either within a cookie (default) or as part of the URL (called URLrewriting, used only if cookies are disabled on the browser). Used to store a session identifier so that New Relic can monitor session counts for an application. | Expires when the session ends  
__insp_norec_sess | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
__insp_nv | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
__insp_slim | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
__insp_targlpt | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
__insp_targlpu | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
__insp_wid | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
ajs_anonymous_id | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
ajs_group_id | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
ajs_user_id | New Relic | Record web site and server's performances on each visit. The data is analyzed in aggregate form and therefore anonymous. | < 2 years  
intercom-id-cyym0u3i | New Relic | These cookies are used by Intercom, a tool used to interact with users and to analyze user behavior. | < 2 years  
optimizelyEndUserId | New Relic | Used to enhance the user's experience and the site appearance. | < 2 years  
ref_page_url | New Relic | Monitor session counts and store unique information about the user. | < 2 years  
  
**Advertising Cookies**  
Advertising cookies are set to display targeted promotions or advertisements based upon your interests on the Website or to manage our advertising. These cookies collect information about your activities on this Website and other websites to provide you targeted advertising.

Cookie | Provider | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
DSID | Google | Advertising cookies on non-Google sites is named ‘IDE‘ and is stored in browsers under the domain doubleclick.net. Used to link user's activity across devices if user has previously signed in to Google Account on another device. | 13 days  
f_id  
| Feathr  
| Set by the CloudFlare service to identify trusted Web traffic. It does not correspond to any user ID in the Web application, nor does the cookie store any personally identifiable information.  
| 1 year  
__cfduid | Feathr  
| Set by the CloudFlare service to identify trusted Web traffic. It does not correspond to any user ID in the Web application, nor does the cookie store any personally identifiable information.  
| 1 year  
IDE | Google | Advertising cookies on non-Google sites is named ‘IDE‘ and is stored in browsers under the domain doubleclick.net. Used to link user's activity across devices if user has previously signed in to Google Account on another device. | 2 years  
__gads | Google | Advertising cookies on non-Google sites is named ‘IDE‘ and is stored in browsers under the domain doubleclick.net. Used to link user's activity across devices if user has previously signed in to Google Account on another device. | 2 years  
x_axis_main | Google | Advertising cookies on non-Google sites is named ‘IDE‘ and is stored in browsers under the domain doubleclick.net. Used to link user's activity across devices if user has previously signed in to Google Account on another device. | 1 year  
x_axis_main | Xasis | These cookies are placed for Media and advertising tracking through Xasis. | < 2 years  
  
If you would like to disable cookies, you can set your web browser to reject cookies. However, if you disable the cookie function, it may make certain features or pages of the Website unavailable to you.; How to alter your cookie setting will depend on the type of browser you use. We have provided examples of how to disable cookies on the most popular browsers below:

Microsoft Internet Explorer

  * choose the "tools" menu then "Internet Options";
  * click on the "privacy" tab; and
  * select the appropriate setting.

Mozilla Firefox:

  * choose the "tools" menu then "Options";
  * click on the "privacy" menu then "Options";
  * click on the "privacy" icon; and
  * find the "cookie" menu and select the relevant options.

Please note that Google and other third parties (including, for example, advertising networks and providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies as a result of your visiting other websites.

Because an industry-standard Do-Not-Track protocol has not yet been established, our information collection practices on our Site will continue to operate as described in this Privacy Policy regardless of any “Do Not Track” signals that may be sent by certain browsers. However, you may refuse to accept cookies in order to prevent tracking activities.

### Sharing Personal Information

We may share your Personal Information with:

  * our IIE offices and affiliates,
  * our service providers and other third parties that make the Website available, enhance its functionality or otherwise provide services to IIE or its service providers,
  * any other person or entity about which we tell you when you provide your Personal Information,
  * and any other person or entity necessary for protecting the rights or safety of IIE or others.

We will not sell, market, share, rent or otherwise distribute your Personal Information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this Policy. Except as otherwise expressly stated in this Policy, we will release Personal Information to another person or company only with your consent or if required or permitted by law. If your Personal Information will be disclosed to any other recipients than are stated in this Policy, we will inform you at the time we collect your Personal Information and obtain your consent.

We do reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers or transferees of any of our assets.

### Bulletin Boards and Chat Areas

Personal Information that you voluntarily disclose and transmit online may be viewed and used by others. Users of the Website are solely responsible for the content of messages and other content they post online, including on public forums. These forums include, but are not limited to, on and offsite chat rooms, bulletin boards, blogs or other publicly accessible forums that may be viewed and used by anyone with access to such forums. You should be aware that when you voluntarily disclose Personal Information within a public forum, your information may be collected and used by others. We cannot control such uses of your Personal Information, and by using such services you assume the risk that the Personal Information provided by you may be viewed and used by third parties.

### International Transfers

We store and process your Personal Information in various countries worldwide including the United States. We may transfer and access such information from around the world, including the United States and other countries in which we operate or in which our hosted service providers’ cloud servers are located so that we can use the information as described in this Policy.

IIE operates this Website from the United States, which has not been deemed to offer adequate data protection by the European Commission. If you provide your Personal Information to us, be aware you are doing so on the basis that you explicitly consent to the transfer of your Personal Information outside the EEA. The potential consequence of you explicitly consenting to this is that there is a risk that your Personal Information will not be protected in a manner that complies with European Data Protection Legislation. You can withdraw your consent to such international transfers by contacting us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org), but if you do, we will not be able to contact you about our Programs and services we may be able to offer you going forward. Where we pass your Personal Information from an IIE entity or office inside the EEA to IIE parties located outside the EEA that do not offer adequate protection as determined by the European Commission, we do this under a data sharing agreement that includes the appropriate EU model international data transfer clauses to make sure your personal information is protected. Where IIE makes transfers of personal information outside IIE to another organization and if they are not subscribed to an approved data protection framework, such as the EU-US Privacy Shield, that permits the transfer of Personal Information to them from the EEA, we rely on the use of the EU model international data transfer clauses if the country the receiving organization is located in is not listed as ‘adequate’ by the European Commission. A copy of the terms of these agreements, signed by the recipient, can be obtained by contacting us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org).

### Security of Personal Information

While we undertake every reasonable effort to prevent unauthorized Internet access to Personal Information we collect, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of information you transmit to us, information provided online, or information stored by us or our service providers. You submit your Personal Information at your own risk. We are not liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or the acts of our service providers or other third parties. This means you accept all risks associated with any data transmission and Internet usage, including the risk that your Personal Information may be intercepted in transit.

### External Links

The Website contains links to third party websites. Unless we state otherwise in writing, IIE makes no representations whatsoever concerning the content or privacy practices or data protection standards of those websites. Our link to a site is not an endorsement, authorization, sponsorship, or affiliation regarding the website, its owners, or its providers. There are risks associated with using any information, software, or products found on the Internet, and IIE cautions you to make sure that you understand these risks before retrieving, using, relying upon, or purchasing anything via the Internet. If you leave the Website and visit other sites, you should carefully read the privacy statements of other websites that collect Personal Information. These other websites may collect or solicit personal data or send their own cookies to your computer. IIE is not responsible for the privacy practices of other websites.

This Policy applies only to this Website and not to any webpages not a part of this Website, even if there are hyperlinks from this Website to another website. As an example, you may decide to connect with us through social media providers that are provided by third parties. The collection, processing, or use of information by such a third party is subject to that third party’s terms of use and privacy policy, and IIE is not responsible for their actions.

### Note to Parents and Children

We comply with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of the United States and similar laws around the world where applicable. Our Site is not specifically targeted to children, we do not actively solicit information from children, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children without proper parental consent. Except in rare cases (such as an inquiry from a university student who is under the age of 18), the Website is not intended for users under the age of 18. If you believe that we may have collected personal information from someone under the applicable age of consent without parental consent, please email us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) and we will promptly address the issue.

### Special California Notice

If you are a resident of California (U.S.A.) under the age of 18 and are a registered user of our Website, you may request that we remove of any content you post to our Website that can be accessed by any other user (whether registered or not). To request removal of content under this provision, please send an email to [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) and provide us with a description of the content and the location of the content on our Site, and any other information we may need to consider your request. Please note that our removal of content under this paragraph does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information posted on the Website by you.

### Retention, Storage and Deletion of Information

IIE retains personal information in line with our corporate retention requirements and policies. We will only save your personal data for as long as it is necessary and relevant for the purpose it was originally collected, until we have no further legitimate interest in the data, you withdraw your consent, or we no longer need to comply with a legal obligation that requires us to retain your Personal Information. More specific information about retention time for processing of personal data in connection with Programs will be provided to you when we collect your Personal Information You have the option, at any time, to request deletion of your Personal Information held by us. However, we may retain a record of the existence of the relationship, to the extent that and for so long as we are required to do so by law (for example, if you have contacted us to ask for the processing of your Personal Information to be erased, we will retain a record of your request to ensure that we comply with your wishes). We may also retain some or all your Personal Information for recordkeeping or legal purposes, to enforce our Terms and Conditions, or as a result of such information being stored on our systems through routine backup or archiving processes. All such cases subject to our corporate retention requirements and policies. All deletion requests should be sent to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org), and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. However, we are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from the lists or systems of any third party unconnected to us who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this Policy.

### Governing Law

The laws of the State of New York (U.S.A.) govern this Policy regardless of your location. By using this Website, you expressly consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in the federal and state courts located in New York, New York, for all matters or disputes arising out of or relating to this Policy or your access or use of the Website.

### Communications and Opting Out

As described above, we may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send surveys or information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our vendors or business partners. But we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you. If you do not wish to receive these types of emails from us, you may “opt-out” by sending an email to us at [siteinfo@iie.org;](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) however, please understand that we may continue sending you emails related to any account you have with us, any application you have submitted, or any transaction or agreement you have entered into with us. There might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to “opt-out” and when it is processed and reflected in our systems, so you may continue to receive certain communications from us for a limited time after you unsubscribe. Any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise via the Website, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions or the like, is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary.

### Certain Users Rights Under GDPR

For users of our Website in the EEA and Switzerland

If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, the following applies.

Purposes of processing and legal basis for processing personal information: As explained above, we process personal information in various ways depending upon your use of the Website. We process personal information on the following legal bases: (1) with your consent; (2) as necessary to perform our agreements; and (3) as necessary for our legitimate interests in providing services where those interests do not override your fundamental rights and freedom related to data privacy.

Individual Rights: If you are a resident of the EEA or Switzerland, you have certain rights under the GDPR. To verify your identity, we might need you to provide us with Personal Information prior to accessing any records containing information about you.

The right to access. You have the right to obtain information about our processing of your personal data and a copy of your personal data that we store.

The right to rectify your data. You have the right to request that we update your personal data if it is inaccurate or incomplete.

The right to request data erasure. You have the right to have your personal information erased from our files if the data is no longer necessary for the purpose for which it was collected, you withdraw your consent and no other legal basis for our processing your data exists, or your fundamental rights to data privacy and protection outweigh our legitimate interest in continuing our processing.

The right to restrict or object to processing. You have the right to restrict or object to our processing if we are processing your data based on legitimate interests or performance of a task in the public interest as an exercise of official authority (including profiling); using your data for direct marketing (including profiling); or processing your data for purposes of scientific or historical research and statistics.

The right to lodge a complaint. If you think we have processed your personal information unfairly or unlawfully, or we have not complied with your rights under GDPR, you have the right to complain to a national data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities are available here.

To submit any request to us under the GDPR, please contact us at the address in the next paragraph for more information.

**Questions and Suggestions**

It is important to us at IIE to hear what visitors and users of the Website think about our services or our policies. If you have any questions, concerns or complaints about this Policy or want to let us know what you think about our services, please contact us using the following information:

IIE.org Site Manager  
Institute of International Education, Inc.  
809 United Nations Plaza  
New York, NY 10017-3580 USA  
E-mail: [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org)

* * *

### Country Specific Terms

**Schedule A**

(Hong Kong)

This Schedule A applies to you if you are submitting information to IIE’s Hong Kong office (otherwise, this Schedule A does not apply to you). This Schedule A modifies certain provisions within the Privacy Policy. All provisions of the Privacy Policy that are not expressly modified in this Schedule continue to apply. The following provisions within the Privacy Policy are modified as follows:

  1. The sentence in the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“You may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) at any time regarding your Personal Information and to request corrections to such information.”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“For further details on direct marketing, please refer to the paragraph headed “Communications, Direct Marketing and Opting Out” below. You may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) at any time regarding your Personal Information and to request access to and corrections to such information and we have the right to charge a reasonable fee for the processing of any data access or correction request.”

2\. The section in the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

**“Communications and Opting Out**

By providing your email address to us, you expressly consent to receive emails from us. We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send surveys or information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our vendors or business partners; however, we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you. If you do not wish to receive these types of emails from us, you may “opt-out” by sending an email to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org); however, please understand that we may continue sending you emails related to any account you have with us, any application you have submitted, or any transaction or agreement you have entered into with us. Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to “opt-out” and when it is processed and reflected in our systems; accordingly, you may continue to receive certain communications from us for a limited time after you unsubscribe. We apologize for any inconvenience and appreciate your patience. Except for Personal Information submitted as part of an application or a purchase, any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions or the like, is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary.”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

**“Communications, Direct Marketing and Opting Out**

From time to time, we may use your Personal Information (including but not limited to name, address, email address and telephone number) or transfer your Personal Information to our representatives, program sponsors or grantors, the affiliates or associated companies or offices of IIE, our business partners in the education sector, our authorized third party services providers, or other person or entity about which we inform you when you provide your Personal Information, for use in promoting and marketing any of our or their events and/or programs (including alumni events and/or promotions) and any other of our or their products or services of which we notify you when you provide your Personal Information. For direct marketing, we may not so use or transfer your Personal Information unless we have received your consent (which includes an indication of no objection). You may indicate your consent when providing us with your Personal Information through the Website or other means. If at any point in time you do not wish us to use your Personal Information for any direct marketing purposes, you may exercise your opt-out rights, without charge to you by notifying our officer at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org). However, please understand that we may continue sending you emails related to any account you have with us, any application you have submitted, or any transaction or agreement you have entered with us. Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to “opt-out” and when it is processed and reflected in our systems; accordingly, you may continue to receive certain communications from us for a limited time after you unsubscribe. We apologize for any inconvenience and appreciate your patience. Except for Personal Information submitted as part of an application or a purchase, any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions or the like, is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary."

* * *

**Schedule B**

(India)

This Schedule B applies to you if you are submitting information to IIE’s India office (otherwise, this Schedule B does not apply to you). This Schedule B modifies certain provisions within the Privacy Policy. All provisions of the Privacy Policy that are not expressly modified in this Schedule continue to apply. The following provisions within the Privacy Policy are modified as follows:

1. The sentence in the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“This Privacy Policy ("Policy") covers the treatment of all personal information that the Institute of International Education, Inc. ("IIE") collects when you visit this website (the "Website").”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“This Privacy Policy ("Policy") covers the treatment of all personal information, including the sensitive personal data or information, that the Institute of International Education, Inc. ("IIE") collects when you visit this website (the "Website").”

The following new section is added to the Privacy Policy:

“ _Sensitive Personal Data or Information (SPD)_. As a part of the Personal Information, we may sometimes require your Sensitive Personal Data or Information (“SPD”) from you for certain purposes. The following SPD may be collected from you:

i. passwords;  
ii. financial information such as bank account or credit card or debit card or other payment instrument details;  
iii. physical, physiological and mental health condition;  
iv. sexual orientation;  
v. medical records and history;  
vi. biometric information; and  
vii. any detail relating to the above (except where any such information listed above does not constitute SPD under applicable law).

Please also note that before collecting any SPD, we need your consent in writing which shall be obtained through the ‘Consent Form’ available on the Website as a part of this Policy. You will be required to give your consent through the Consent Form duly signed by you and submitted to us either through fax or email.”

3\. The following sentence is added to the Privacy Policy:

“Where the Personal Information to be shared with third parties as provided in this Policy constitutes SPD, we will obtain your prior consent in writing through the Consent Form described in this Policy before sharing such SPD.”

4\. The provision in the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“Please note that we do reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers or transferees of any of our assets.”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“Please note that we do reserve the right to transfer your Personal Information and other information to our successors in business and purchasers or transferees of any of our assets. If such transfer involves the transfer of SPD, we will only transfer such SPD if we have obtained your prior consent in writing.”

5\. The following provision is added to the Privacy Policy:

“You also have the option, at any time while availing yourself of the services or otherwise, to withdraw your consent given earlier to IIE. Your withdrawal of consent shall be sent in writing to IIE. In case of withdrawal of your consent, IIE reserves the option not to provide the services for which the Personal Information, including the SPD, was sought. For withdrawing your consent, you may send an e-mail to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org). Your withdrawal will become effective upon the receipt of an acknowledgment by you from us.

6\. The following provision is added to the Privacy Policy:

“Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Policy, we will delete your SPD when it is no longer required to be retained for the purposes for which it was collected or otherwise required under any law. When obtaining your consent for collecting the SPD, the Consent Form will also prescribe the period of retention of your SPD.”

7\. The following provision is added to the Privacy Policy:

“We strive to ensure the security, integrity, protection and privacy of your Personal Information against unauthorized access or unauthorized alteration, disclosure or destruction. We use reasonable security techniques for handling your Personal Information, including the SPD. These techniques and requirements are fully compliant with the guidelines set forth under the applicable laws. Your information logged under this Privacy Policy is shared with respective personnel only on need to know basis and/or to provide the services you have requested. All representatives handling information under these provisions are under confidentiality obligations to us.”

8\. The following provision is added to the Privacy Policy:

**“Grievance Officer**

If you have any grievance regarding the processing of your information, please contact our Grievance Officer whose details are given as under:

Name: Priya Ranjan Pradhan  
Direct Landline: +91.11.26516870  
E-mail: [ppradhan@iie.org](mailto:ppradhan@iie.org)"

* * *

**Schedule C**

(Mexico)

This Schedule C applies to you if you are a resident of Mexico or submitting information to an IIE office in Mexico (otherwise, this Schedule C does not apply to you). This Schedule C modifies certain provisions within the Privacy Policy. All provisions of the Privacy Policy that are not expressly modified in this Schedule continue to apply. The following provisions within the Privacy Policy are modified as follows:

1\. The sentence in the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“You may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) at any time regarding your Personal Information and to request corrections to such information."

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“You may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) at any time regarding your Personal Information and to request access, corrections to such information, to limit its use and disclosure, or to object to the processing of your Personal Information. Please note that limits you place on, or objections you make to, the use, disclosure or processing of your Personal Information might result in your no longer being eligible for, or continuing your application for, certain grants or programs (where the Personal Information is required for such grants, programs or applications).”

* * *

**Schedule D**

(Russia)

This Schedule D applies to you if you are submitting information to IIE’s office in Russia or if you reside in Russia (otherwise, this Schedule D does not apply to you). This Schedule D modifies certain provisions within the Privacy Policy. All provisions of the Privacy Policy that are not expressly modified in this Schedule continue to apply. The following provisions within the Privacy Policy are modified as follows:

1\. The following provision of the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“ **Personal Information Examples**

Aside from this standard tracking data, the only personal information we collect about you is such personally identifiable data ("Personal Information") as you knowingly provide to us on the Website. Personal Information can include your name, birth date, gender, email address, physical address and telephone number, financial information and/or other personal information you may provide. Except as provided otherwise by law or pursuant to this policy, IIE is the sole owner of any information collected on the Website”.

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“ **Personal Information Examples**

Aside from this standard tracking data, the only personal information we collect about you is such personally identifiable data ("Personal Information") as you knowingly provide to us on the Website. Personal Information can include your name, birth date, gender, email address, physical address and telephone number, financial information, marital status, passport information, Individual Taxpayer Number, information about your education, health condition and medical records (only of successful applicants) and/or other personal information you may provide. Except as provided otherwise by law or pursuant to this policy, IIE is the sole owner of any information collected on the Website”.

2\. The following provision of the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“ **Governing Law**

The laws of the State of New York shall govern this Policy regardless of your location. You hereby expressly consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in the federal and state courts located in New York, New York, for all matters or disputes arising out of or relating to this Policy or your access or use of the Website.”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“ **Governing Law**

This Privacy Policy is governed by the laws of the Russian Federation”

3\. The following provision of the Privacy Policy that reads as follows:

“If you do not want to provide us with your Personal Information, you are not required to do so; however, while you may still access the Website, certain services may not be available to you. By providing your Personal Information to us via the Website, you consent to receive information and updates from us, our representatives or our authorized third-party service providers (except where prohibited by law). You may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) at any time regarding your Personal Information and to request corrections to such information"

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“When you submit your Personal Information to us we request you to provide a specific consent to our operations with it. If you do not want to provide us with your Personal Information, you are not required to do so; however, while you may still access the Website, certain services may not be available to you.

While providing your Personal Information to us via the Website, you may additionally consent to receive the information and updates from us, our representatives or our authorized third-party service providers (except where prohibited by law). Such consent can be expressed through the special electronic form on the Website or by any other means (email, paper format, etc.). If you do not wish to receive such information any longer, you may inform us about this decision by sending an email to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org).

Please also note that you may contact us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org) any time if you have any questions, queries or correction requests about your Personal Information”

4\. The following provision of the Privacy policy that reads as follows:

“ **Security of Personal Information**

While we undertake reasonable efforts to prevent unauthorized Internet access to user data we collect from you, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online or stored by us or our service providers, and you submit such Personal Information at your own risk. You agree that we are not liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or the acts of our service providers or other third parties. You accept all risks associated with any data transmission and Internet usage, including the risk that your Personal Information may be intercepted in transit”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“ **Security of Personal Information**

While we undertake all necessary and sufficient legal, organizational and technical measures required by the Russian legislation on personal data protection to ensure security of data we collect from you, we cannot ensure or warrant the absolute security of any information you transmit to us or any information provided online or stored by us or our service providers, and you submit such Personal Information at your own risk. You agree that we are not liable for disclosures of your Personal Information due to errors in transmission or the acts of our service providers or other third parties. You accept all risks associated with any data transmission and Internet usage, including the risk that your Personal Information may be intercepted in transit”.

5\. The following provision of the Privacy policy that reads as follows:

“ **Retention, Storage and Deletion of Information**

You have the option, at any time, to request deletion of your Personal Information held by us; however, we may retain some or all your Personal Information for recordkeeping or legal purposes, to enforce our Terms and Conditions, or as a result of such information being stored on our systems through routine backup or archiving processes. All deletion requests should be sent to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org), and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. However, we are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from the lists or systems of any third party who has previously been provided your information in accordance with this Policy”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“ **Retention, Storage and Deletion of Information**

You have the option, at any time, to revoke your consent for processing of your Personal Information and to request deletion of your Personal Information held by us. All deletion requests should be sent to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org), and we will process your request within a reasonable time after receipt. However, we are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from the lists or systems of all other third parties who have previously been provided your information in accordance with this Policy.

Please note that in some cases we may retain some or all your Personal Information even after you request us to delete it, if we are obligated to do so by applicable legislation”

6\. The following provision of the Privacy policy the reads as follows:

“ **Communications and Opting Out**

By providing your email address to us, you expressly consent to receive emails from us. We may use email to communicate with you, to send information that you have requested or to send surveys or information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our vendors or business partners; however, we will not give your email address to another party to promote their products or services directly to you. If you do not wish to receive these types of emails from us, you may “opt-out” by sending an email to us at [siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org); however, please understand that we may continue sending you emails related to any account you have with us, any application you have submitted, or any transaction or agreement you have entered into with us. Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to “opt-out” and when it is processed and reflected in our systems; accordingly, you may continue to receive certain communications from us for a limited time after you unsubscribe. We apologize for any inconvenience and appreciate your patience. Except for Personal Information submitted as part of an application or a purchase, any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions or the like, is, and will be treated as, non-confidential and nonproprietary”

is deleted and replaced with the following:

“ **Communications and Opting Out**

****By providing your email address to us, you consent that we may use your email to communicate with you and to send information that you have requested. At the same time, we will not use email for marketing and promoting purposes such as sending surveys or information about other products or services developed or provided by us or our vendors or business partners without your specific consent to it. Such consent can be expressed through the special electronic form on the Website or by any other means (email, paper format, etc.). If you do not wish to receive these types of emails from us, you may inform us about this decision by sending an email to us at[siteinfo@iie.org](mailto:siteinfo@iie.org).

However, please understand that we may continue sending you nonmarketing emails related to any account you have with us, any application you have submitted, or any transaction or agreement you have entered with us.

Please note that there might be a brief delay between when you submit your request to unsubscribe and when it is processed and reflected in our systems; accordingly, you may continue to receive certain communications from us for a limited time after you unsubscribe. We apologize for any inconvenience and appreciate your patience. Except for Personal Information submitted as part of an application or a purchase, any communication or material you transmit to us by email or otherwise, including any data, questions, comments, suggestions or the like, is, and will be treated as, non-confidential.
